{
    "id": "8b9bd06b5cf949da95bb6efa19f2bcf4",
    "title": "Question Tags And Short Answers",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "55eb15f74b4245c1a23960c9df69c358",
            "title": "Question Tags And Short Answers",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Your sister sings well, …………………….?",
                    "description": "We make question tags in the simple present tense with do and does. Note that we use a negative tag after an affirmative sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "does she",
                        "doesn't she",
                        "hasn't she"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Samuel passed the test, …………………….?",
                    "description": "In the simple past tense we make question tags with did.",
                    "answers": [
                        "doesn't he",
                        "did he",
                        "didn't he"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She recognized him, ……………………..?",
                    "description": "In the simple past tense we make question tags with did.",
                    "answers": [
                        "hadn't she",
                        "didn't she",
                        "doesn't she"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Someone wanted a drink, ……………………..?",
                    "description": "In question tags we use they to refer to somebody. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "did they",
                        "didn't he",
                        "didn't they"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You like mushrooms, ……………………..?",
                    "description": "We make question tags in the simple present tense with do and does. Note that we use a negative tag after an affirmative sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "do you",
                        "don't you",
                        "didn't you"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He works hard, ……………………….?",
                    "description": "We make question tags in the simple present tense with do and does. Note that we use a negative tag after an affirmative sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "does he",
                        "doesn't he",
                        "hasn't he"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘Is your son married?’ ‘Yes, he ………………..’",
                    "description": "Affirmative short answers have the form ‘Yes + pronoun + auxiliary’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "has",
                        "married"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘He took the money.’ ‘No, he ……………………’",
                    "description": "Negative short answers have the form ‘No + pronoun + auxiliary + n’t’",
                    "answers": [
                        "doesn't",
                        "did",
                        "didn't"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He doesn’t speak German. …………………….. do I.",
                    "description": "Negative additions to negative statements are made with ‘nor / neither + auxiliary + subject’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Neither",
                        "Nor",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She can’t swim. Neither ……………………..",
                    "description": "Negative additions to negative statements are made with ‘nor / neither + auxiliary + subject’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "I can",
                        "can I",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "My husband loves music. …………………. do I.",
                    "description": "Affirmative additions to affirmative statements are made with ‘so + auxiliary + subject’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Neither",
                        "Nor",
                        "So"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘I didn’t hear the sound.’ ‘……………………. did I.’",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Neither",
                        "So",
                        "Of course"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}